<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unique Divine</title>
    <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Unique Divine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://uniquedivine.blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a programmer that makes music and writes. I&amp;rsquo;m obsessed with learning, solving problems, and creating, whether this involves artwork, music, coding, whatever. To learn and create is my ikigai (生き甲斐).
§ — What I do for work I&amp;rsquo;m a Co-Founder and one of the lead software engineers for a new DeFi hub called Nibiru Chain. I&amp;rsquo;m also an open-source contributor in the broader Cosmos and Ethereum Ecosystems.
§ — Noteworthy open-source code Repository Description 🐍 python-crypto-api-wrappers A Python package for wrapping common Cryptocurrency APIs such as Messari, Coin Market Cap, Etherscan, CoinGecko, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Going - by Austin Kleon</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/post/books/keep-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/post/books/keep-going/</guid>
      <description>[Amazon link] to support the author Lately, something&amp;rsquo;s got me in a phase where I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in reading books about making art—like Art &amp;amp; Fear and Keep Going. I believe I first heard about Kleon&amp;rsquo;s writing from Ali Abdaal.
Keep Going sticks to Kleon&amp;rsquo;s classic, pocket-sized, lighthearted but heavy-hitting style. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick read, so I went through it a few times. With books like this, I like to make one pass through to jot down quotes and notes on passages that resonate with me and then wrestle with the ideas for a while before coming back to the text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GANs for Genomics</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/gans-for-genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/gans-for-genomics/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Multiple papers have shown that neural networks are generally less effective for prediction of complex genetic disorders than polygenic risk scores (PRSs) even though PRSs are linear predictors [Pinto et al., 2019] [Mamani, 2020] [Badré et al., 2020]. I found this surprising at first but grew to understand why after discovering what challenges arrise when working with genomics datasets for predictive modeling.
High-dimensionality feature sets: Input vectors can have on the order of 100,000+ features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexing on my checklists</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/post/poh/flexing-on-my-checklists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/post/poh/flexing-on-my-checklists/</guid>
      <description>A quick note on scheduling. To-do lists and schedules are great tools with obvious utility. They help us keep our lives from becoming too chaotic and make it easier to &amp;ldquo;steer the ship&amp;rdquo; toward long-term goals. As someone who used to struggle with organization, I benefit a lot from utilizing strucured strategies such as the Getting Things Done (GTD) system and from convenient tools like schedules and Todoist. In spite of this, I often find myself unable to keep up with the some of the schedules and daily goals I set for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Reflection &amp; Logging 「過去を顧みること」</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/post/poh/reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/post/poh/reflection/</guid>
      <description>I like to dream as much as anyone. However, I&amp;rsquo;m also a huge fan of results and tangible evidence.
I was an athlete for probably 10 years of my life and so I&amp;rsquo;d tried a multitude of different strength and conditioning programs, diets, and exercise methods. There was a point in time where I was doing a more intense phase of bodybuilding from the tail end of high school leading into my first few years of college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why&#39;d I learn Japanese again?</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/post/japanese/why_learn_jp_again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/post/japanese/why_learn_jp_again/</guid>
      <description>I recently crossed the 10,000 sentence mark in my dearly beloved spaced repitition software (SRS), Anki, after noticing that my deck includes 10,317 mature sentence cards.
At the onset of my learning journey, I was excited and inspired by Khatzumoto&amp;rsquo;s progress and figured I could learn a thing or two by temporarily giving in to dogma.
This milestone took me roughly two years of consistent grinding, where I averaged between 60-200 minutes of daily study time depending on the month and my availability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks for Gravitational Lens Modeling</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/nn-grav_lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/nn-grav_lens/</guid>
      <description>Neural Networks for Gravitational Lens Modeling In this project, I use convolutional neural networks (with TensorFlow) to estimate the parameters of strong gravitational lenses, namely the coordinates of the center of the lens in two dimensions, the Einstein radius, and the complex ellipticities.
These parameters are important because they enable us to quantify the distortions of images due to gravitational lensing. The fact that the deflection of light due to gravitational lensing is dependent on the mass structure of the lens means that recovering these parameters effectively allows us to measure and characterize the distribution of mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Click-Through Rate Prediction with Stochastic Gradient Descent</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/ctr-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/ctr-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Motivation: Click-through rate (CTR) is the ratio of users who click on a link to the number of users who see it. It is commonly used to measure the success of marketing campaigns.
The goal of this project is to predict whether advertisements will be clicked or not. In solving this problem, I implement a stochastic gradient descent algorithm called Pegasos, which has proven to be effective for CTR predictions in the past (Sculley et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banknote Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/banknote_fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/banknote_fraud/</guid>
      <description>Banknote Fraud Detection - Decision Trees from Scratch The goal of this project was to develop accurate predictive models to solve a binary classification problem: detecting fraudulent banknotes. I figured that learning to write decision tree algorithms from scratch could serve as an effective technical exercise. Unexpectedly, this from-scratch implementation ended up outperforming the default trees from Scikit-learn.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to view the notebook without downloading anything, go here: Data Description: The data was downloaded from this source.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
