<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unique Divine</title>
    <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Unique Divine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://unique-divine.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Reflection &amp; Logging 「過去を顧みること」</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/poh/reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/poh/reflection/</guid>
      <description>I like to dream as much as anyone. However, I&amp;rsquo;m also a huge fan of results and tangible evidence.
I was an athlete for probably 10 years of my life and so I&amp;rsquo;d tried a multitude of different strength and conditioning programs, diets, and exercise methods. There was a point in time where I was doing a more intense phase of bodybuilding from the tail end of high school leading into my first few years of college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there, I&amp;rsquo;m Unique Divine.
I&amp;rsquo;m a musician, a writer, a programmer, and an artist.
I love to solve interesting problems and build stuff.
Current Foci:  💻 A deep reinforcement learning (RL) research project with Erik Skalnes: We&amp;rsquo;re integrating an attention mechanism into the actor-critic method in a way that may allow the RL agent to interpret memories 💰 Leading and collaborating with an algorithmic trading 👯 &amp;ldquo;dream team&amp;rdquo; 📚 Graduate school at Columbia University 🤖 Artificial intelligence engineering work @ Applied Technology Solutions, Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why&#39;d I learn Japanese again?</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/japanese/why_learn_jp_again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/japanese/why_learn_jp_again/</guid>
      <description>I recently crossed the 10,000 sentence mark in my dearly beloved spaced repitition software (SRS), Anki, after noticing that my deck includes 10,317 mature sentence cards.
At the onset of my learning journey, I was excited and inspired by Khatzumoto&amp;rsquo;s progress and figured I could learn a thing or two by temporarily giving in to dogma.
This milestone took me roughly two years of consistent grinding, where I averaged between 60-200 minutes of daily study time depending on the month and my availability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks for Gravitational Lens Modeling</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/projects/nn-grav_lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/projects/nn-grav_lens/</guid>
      <description>Neural Networks for Gravitational Lens Modeling In this project, I use convolutional neural networks (with TensorFlow) to estimate the parameters of strong gravitational lenses, namely the coordinates of the center of the lens in two dimensions, the Einstein radius, and the complex ellipticities.
These parameters are important because they enable us to quantify the distortions of images due to gravitational lensing. The fact that the deflection of light due to gravitational lensing is dependent on the mass structure of the lens means that recovering these parameters effectively allows us to measure and characterize the distribution of mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Click-Through Rate Prediction with Stochastic Gradient Descent</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/projects/ctr-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/projects/ctr-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Motivation: Click-through rate (CTR) is the ratio of users who click on a link to the number of users who see it. It is commonly used to measure the success of marketing campaigns.
The goal of this project is to predict whether advertisements will be clicked or not. In solving this problem, I implement a stochastic gradient descent algorithm called Pegasos, which has proven to be effective for CTR predictions in the past (Sculley et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banknote Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/projects/banknote_fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/projects/banknote_fraud/</guid>
      <description>Banknote Fraud Detection - Decision Trees from Scratch Summary: The goal of this project was to develop accurate predictive models to solve a binary classification problem, detecting fraudulent banknotes (counterfeit money).
To view the notebook without downloading anything, go here.
Data Description: The data was downloaded from this source.
 Extracted from images were taken from genuine and forged banknote-like specimens. For digitization, an industrial camera usually used for print inspection was used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Into Data Science I: Plan of Attack</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/ai/breaking-into-ds-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/ai/breaking-into-ds-i/</guid>
      <description>In 5th grade, one of my classmates fell down and broke his arm during a game of two-hand touch football, so the elementary school banned the sport during recess. I was pretty upset about this. Lots of kids were. This was Texas, after all, and we loved our football.
I experimented with other recess activities: hopscotch, double Dutch, chalk drawing, tetherball, basketball, dodgeball, kickball. Many of these activities just didn&amp;rsquo;t do it for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>