<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on Unique Divine</title>
    <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on Unique Divine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://unique-divine.github.io/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Undefeated: How to Make Battle Plans For Life</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/ai/going_undefeated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/ai/going_undefeated/</guid>
      <description>Last Summer, I made the declaration to transition from PhD physics track to industry data scientist in under a year. That is, by June of this year.
As this is somewhat of a hot field, I realized that this wil take a great deal of transformation and growth on my part. In my current state, I&amp;rsquo;m far from the ideal candidate listed in these job descriptions. My undergraduate background isn&amp;rsquo;t in computer science, data science, or statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Into Data Science II:</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/ai/breaking-into-ds-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/ai/breaking-into-ds-ii/</guid>
      <description>I heard somebody say a few weeks back to “teach the thing you want to learn”. It seemed a bit paradoxical at first, but I decided to wrestle with the idea a bit:
 “How can I teach something when I don’t know much about it? How can I give someone useful advice about how to accomplish a goal that I’ve been unsuccesful in up to this point? I&amp;rsquo;ll become a canonical example of the blind leading the blind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Into Data Science I: Plan of Attack</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/ai/breaking-into-ds-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/ai/breaking-into-ds-i/</guid>
      <description>In 5th grade, one of my classmates fell down and broke his arm during a game of two-hand touch football, so the elementary school banned the sport during recess. I was pretty upset about this. Lots of kids were. This was Texas, afterall, and we loved our football.
I experimented with other recess activies: hopscotch, double dutch, chalk drawing, tetherball, basketball, dodgeball, kickball. Many of these activites just didn&amp;rsquo;t do it for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>