<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Posts on Unique Divine</title>
    <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Posts on Unique Divine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://unique-divine.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexing on my checklists</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/poh/flexing-on-my-checklists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/poh/flexing-on-my-checklists/</guid>
      <description>A quick note on scheduling. To-do lists and schedules are great tools with obvious utility. They help us keep our lives from becoming too chaotic and make it easier to &amp;ldquo;steer the ship&amp;rdquo; toward long-term goals. As someone who used to struggle with organization, I benefit a lot from utilizing strucured strategies such as the Getting Things Done (GTD) system and from convenient tools like schedules and Todoist. Inspite of this, I often find myself unable to keep up with the some of the schedules and daily goals I set for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Reflection &amp; Logging 「過去を顧みること」</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/poh/reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/poh/reflection/</guid>
      <description>I like to dream as much as anyone. However, I&amp;rsquo;m also a huge fan of results and tangible evidence.
I was an athlete for probably 10 years of my life and so I&amp;rsquo;d tried a multitude of different strength and conditioning programs, diets, and exercise methods. There was a point in time where I was doing a more intense phase of bodybuilding from the tail end of high school leading into my first few years of college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why&#39;d I learn Japanese again?</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/japanese/why_learn_jp_again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/japanese/why_learn_jp_again/</guid>
      <description>I recently crossed the 10,000 sentence mark in my dearly beloved spaced repitition software (SRS), Anki, after noticing that my deck includes 10,317 mature sentence cards.
At the onset of my learning journey, I was excited and inspired by Khatzumoto&amp;rsquo;s progress and figured I could learn a thing or two by temporarily giving in to dogma.
This milestone took me roughly two years of consistent grinding, where I averaged between 60-200 minutes of daily study time depending on the month and my availability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Into Data Science I: Plan of Attack</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/ai/breaking-into-ds-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/ai/breaking-into-ds-i/</guid>
      <description>I just finished undergrad at Columbia University a few days ago. We had a virtual ceremony, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to watch it. I over-exhausted myself this past semester and no longer have the energy left to celebrate. With that said, now&amp;rsquo;s as good a time as any to address some of my big picture ambitions.
Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve developed an effective system for accomplishing long-term goals such as learning a language, mastering a musical instrument, transitioning fields to a new discipline, and integrating exercise into one&amp;rsquo;s life as a regular habit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>