<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data science on Unique Divine</title>
    <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data science on Unique Divine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://unique-divine.github.io/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks for Gravitational Lens Modeling</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/projects/nn-grav_lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/projects/nn-grav_lens/</guid>
      <description>Neural Networks for Gravitational Lens Modeling In this project, I use convolutional neural networks (with TensorFlow) to estimate the parameters of strong gravitational lenses, namely the coordinates of the center of the lens in two dimensions, the Einstein radius, and the complex ellipticities.
These parameters are important because they enable us to quantify the distortions of images due to gravitational lensing. The fact that the deflection of light due to gravitational lensing is dependent on the mass structure of the lens means that recovering these parameters effectively allows us to measure and characterize the distribution of mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Click-Through Rate Prediction with Stochastic Gradient Descent</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/projects/ctr-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/projects/ctr-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Motivation: Click-through rate (CTR) is the ratio of users who click on a link to the number of users who see it. It is commonly used to measure the success of marketing campaigns.
The goal of this project is to predict whether advertisements will be clicked or not. In solving this problem, I implement a stochastic gradient descent algorithm called Pegasos, which has proven to be effective for CTR predictions in the past (Sculley et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Into Data Science</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/ai/breaking-into-ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/post/ai/breaking-into-ds/</guid>
      <description>This post comes at a time where I, myself, am feeling the first-hire blues.
An overall sense of burnout, frustration, confusion.
I’ve gotten well acquainted with the phrases,
“We reget to inform you at this time…”,
“Although we were impressed with your interview/qualifications…”,
“[insert insincere compliment here]. Unfortunately, [insert rejection statement here] …”.
I heard somebody say a few weeks back to “teach the thing you want to learn”.` It seemed a bit paradoxical the first time I thought about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banknote Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>https://unique-divine.github.io/projects/banknote_fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unique-divine.github.io/projects/banknote_fraud/</guid>
      <description>Banknote Fraud Detection - Decision Trees from Scratch Summary: The goal of this project was to develop accurate predictive models to solve a binary classification problem, detecting fraudulent banknotes (counterfeit money).
To view the notebook without downloading anything, go here.
Data Description: The data was downloaded from this source.
 Extracted from images were taken from genuine and forged banknote-like specimens. For digitization, an industrial camera usually used for print inspection was used.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>