<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data science on Unique Divine</title>
    <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data science on Unique Divine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://uniquedivine.blog/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GANs for Genomics</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/gans-for-genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/gans-for-genomics/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Multiple papers have shown that neural networks are generally less effective for prediction of complex genetic disorders than polygenic risk scores (PRSs) even though PRSs are linear predictors [Pinto et al., 2019] [Mamani, 2020] [Badré et al., 2020]. I found this surprising at first but grew to understand why after discovering what challenges arrise when working with genomics datasets for predictive modeling.
High-dimensionality feature sets: Input vectors can have on the order of 100,000+ features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks for Gravitational Lens Modeling</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/nn-grav_lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/nn-grav_lens/</guid>
      <description>Neural Networks for Gravitational Lens Modeling In this project, I use convolutional neural networks (with TensorFlow) to estimate the parameters of strong gravitational lenses, namely the coordinates of the center of the lens in two dimensions, the Einstein radius, and the complex ellipticities.
These parameters are important because they enable us to quantify the distortions of images due to gravitational lensing. The fact that the deflection of light due to gravitational lensing is dependent on the mass structure of the lens means that recovering these parameters effectively allows us to measure and characterize the distribution of mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Click-Through Rate Prediction with Stochastic Gradient Descent</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/ctr-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/ctr-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Motivation: Click-through rate (CTR) is the ratio of users who click on a link to the number of users who see it. It is commonly used to measure the success of marketing campaigns.
The goal of this project is to predict whether advertisements will be clicked or not. In solving this problem, I implement a stochastic gradient descent algorithm called Pegasos, which has proven to be effective for CTR predictions in the past (Sculley et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banknote Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/banknote_fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uniquedivine.blog/projects/banknote_fraud/</guid>
      <description>Banknote Fraud Detection - Decision Trees from Scratch The goal of this project was to develop accurate predictive models to solve a binary classification problem: detecting fraudulent banknotes. I figured that learning to write decision tree algorithms from scratch could serve as an effective technical exercise. Unexpectedly, this from-scratch implementation ended up outperforming the default trees from Scikit-learn.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to view the notebook without downloading anything, go here: Data Description: The data was downloaded from this source.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
